Guide to the Time Inc. Postal Rates Records 1949-1978 (bulk, 1969-1978 MS 3009-RG 57
New-York Historical Society
Time Inc. Postal Rates Records
1949-1978 (bulk, 1969-1978)
New-York Historical Society
Time, inc.
MS 3009-RG 57
17 Linear feet in 16 record cartons
When postal rates or other aspects of law governing postal delivery were changed, or may be changed, in ways Time Inc. found unfavorable, it advocated for its position with Congress and the public. This collection contains information used in those activities such as bills put before Congress on the topic of postal rates and law, correspondence between people within Time Inc. and with members of Congress, proceedings of the Postal Commission including witness testimony, reports on the costs of postal delivery, and examples of Time Inc.'s direct mail marketing.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.
Open to qualified researchers with the exception of restricted materials. Restricted materials include contracts and are located in box R86.
Arrangement
The materials within the Time Inc. Postal Rates Records record group are organized into six series: Series I. Time Inc. Preparations for Cases; Series II. Mail Classification Schedule Proceedings; Series III. Cost Ascertainment Reports; Series IV. Direct Mail Exhibits; Series V. Raymond J. Mitchell Files; and Series VI. Winston H. Cox Files.
Historical Note
Being primarily in the business of selling magazines that must be shipped to subscribers and newsstands, Time Inc. was a heavy user of the postal system and was sensitive to increases in postal rates and other changes in classification of mail. When unfavorable changes to rates and/or laws were proposed by the Postal Rate Commission (PRC) or Congress in the late 1960s and early-to-mid 1970s, Time Inc., along with other publishers, advocated for their positions by contacting members of Congress and running articles in Time to explain their position to the public. Two individuals at Time Inc. particularly represented in this collection are Raymond J. "Ray" Mitchell's, Director of Time Inc.'s Alternative Distribution Program, and Winston H. "Tony" Cox, Assistant to the Group Vice-President for Magazines.
Custodial History
Gift of Time Inc. in 2015.
Related Materials
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. Records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. Records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of files kept as information for Time Inc. advocacy efforts and includes copies of bills put before Congress on the topic of postal rates and law, correspondence between people within Time Inc. and with members of Congress, presentations produced on the subjects of postal costs by Time Inc. personnel, proceedings of the Postal Commission including witness testimony and questions to witness from Time Inc. and other parties, reports from the United States Post Office Department on the costs of delivery, and examples of Time Inc.'s direct mail marketing.
Corporation records; Corporations -- History; Corporations -- New York (State) -- New York.; Legal documents.; Organization files; Postal rates -- United States; Publishers and publishing -- New York (State) -- New York.; Time, inc. -- Archives; Time, inc. -- History
- Series I. Time Inc. Preparations for Cases, 1952-1975; 2 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
  Scope and Contents
  Series I consists of information used by Time Inc. to prepare internally for legal arguments regarding changes in postal rates and law. Memos between Time Inc. employees are prevalent along with outside information sources such as magazine articles, reports on congressional sessions, and presentations created based on the gathered information.
  Arrangement
  Series I is in alphabetical order.
  - Ablard, Charles, 1962-1965 (Offsite-box 4215, Folder 1)
  - Blueprint for Change: Canada Post Office, 1969 (Offsite-box 4215, Folder 2)
  - Book II: Report on Third Class Mail, 1953 (Offsite-box 4215, Folder 3)
  - Cost Ascertainment Report (C.A.R.) Statistical Approximation, 1952-1953 (Offsite-box 4215, Folder 4-5)
  - Cost Ascertainment Reports, 1947, 1957 (Offsite-box 4215, Folder 6)
  - Coronet Article, 1957 (Offsite-box 4215, Folder 7)
  - Exhibit A: Post Office Presentation Pictures: Negatives, 1956 (Offsite-box 4215, Folder 8)
  - Exhibit B: Questions and Answers, 1960 (Offsite-box 4215, Folder 9)
  - House, March 1957 (Offsite-box 4215, Folder 10)
  - House: 1960 (May) (Offsite-box 4215, Folder 11)
  - House 1961 (May) (Offsite-box 4215, Folder 12-13)
  - Legal Fees [Restricted], 1967 (Offsite-box R86)
  - Life Booklet, 1957 (Offsite-box 4215, Folder 14)
  - Life Photo Exhibits, undated (Offsite-box 4215, Folder 15)
  - List of Appearances, undated (Offsite-box 4215, Folder 16)
  - Magazine Publishers Association, Inc., 1953-1958 (Offsite-box 4215, Folder 17)
  - Magazine Publishers Association: Memoranda, 1963 (Offsite-box 4215, Folder 18)
  - Memos, 1965-1975 (Offsite-box 4215, Folder 19)
  - Memos, 1965-1975 (Offsite-box 4216, Folder 1)
  - Policy and Supporting Positions, 1968 (Offsite-box 4216, Folder 2)
  - Post Office Charts, circa 1956 (Offsite-box 4216, Folder 3-4)
  - Postal Photostats, undated (Offsite-box 4216, Folder 5)
  - Postal Presentation, 1953-1963 (Offsite-box 4216, Folder 6-8)
  - Postal Testimony: Statistics: 1962 April (Offsite-box 4216, Folder 9)
  - Postmaster Correspondence, 1957 (Offsite-box 4216, Folder 10)
  - Proposed, 1957-1958 (Offsite-box 4216, Folder 11)
  - Publications Exempt from Zone Rates, circa 1952 (Offsite-box 4216, Folder 12)
  - Pull-Out: 2nd Class Rate Problem, 1960 (Offsite-box 4216, Folder 13)
  - Senate Appropriations, 1961 (Offsite-box 4216, Folder 14)
  - Senate: 1st Presentation (Not Given), 1954 (Offsite-box 4216, Folder 15)
  - Senate: 1962 (April) (Offsite-box 4216, Folder 16-17)
  - Testimony, 1969 (Offsite-box 4216, Folder 18)
- Series II. Mail Classification Schedule Proceedings, 1969-1977; 10.2 Linear feet in 11 record cartons
  Series II is composed of reports from congressional proceedings on postal rates and law. This includes witness testimony, questions given and answered to and by various parties, and proposed legislation.
  Series II is arranged alphabetically.
  - Alternate Delivery, 1971-1975 (Offsite-box 4217, Folder 1-10)
  - American Business Press (ABP), 1971-1974 (Offsite-box 4217, Folder 11)
  - Arthur Keylor, 1971 (Offsite-box 4217, Folder 12-13)
  - Associated Third Class Mail Users (ATCMU)/Direct Mail Advertising Association (DMMA), 1973-1976 (Offsite-box 4217, Folder 14)
  - Austell, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 4217, Folder 15-16)
  - Board, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 4217, Folder 17-18)
  - Clark Clifford, etc., Robert Keeler, A.H. Letter to Ford, Time Editorial (empty), undated (Offsite-box 4217, Folder 19)
  - Classification Schedule: 1973: Official Transcript (Offsite-box 4217, Folder 20)
  - Classification: Phase II, 1974-1976 (Offsite-box 4217, Folder 21-22)
  - Cost of Living Council, 1973 (Offsite-box 4217, Folder 23-25)
  - Cost of Living Council, 1973 (Offsite-box 4217, Folder 1-4)
  - Data, 1975 (Offsite-box 4218, Folder 5)
  - Dow Jones, 1974 (Offsite-box 4218, Folder 6-7)
  - Evan Ingels, 1974 (Offsite-box 4218, Folder 8)
  - Exhibits on Life Suspension, 1973 (Offsite-box 4218, Folder 9-10)
  - Filings by Time Inc. and Magazine Publishers Association (MPA), 1976 (Offsite-box 4218, Folder 11-12)
  - Home Delivery Firms, 1976 (Offsite-box 4218, Folder 13-15)
  - Idea Release Form, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 4218, Folder 16)
  - Initial Brief, 1976 (Offsite-box 4218, Folder 17-18)
  - Klassen: United States Postal Service, 1974 (Offsite-box 4218, Folder 19)
  - Legislative, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 4218, Folder 20-23)
  - Louis Cox Statements, 1975 (Offsite-box 4218, Folder 24)
  - MC73-1: Postal Classification, 1976 (Offsite-box 4218, Folder 25)
  - MC73-1: Richard J. Barber Testimony, 1974 (Offsite-box 4218, Folder 26)
  - Magazine Publishers Association (MPA), 1971-1977 (Offsite-box 4219, Folder 1-6)
  - Mail Classification Proceedings, 1975-1977 (Offsite-box 4219, Folder 7-16)
  - Mail Classification Proceedings, 1975-1977 (Offsite-box 4220, Folder 1-14)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970-1976 (Offsite-box 4221, Folder 10-11)
  - National Postal Forum IX, 1975 (Offsite-box 4221, Folder 12)
  - Notice of Inquiry, 1976 (Offsite-box 4221, Folder 13)
  - Opinion and Recommended Decision, 1972 (Offsite-box 4221, Folder 14)
  - Ottawa Hearings, 1970 (Offsite-box 4221, Folder 15)
  - Phase I Classification, 1976 (Offsite-box 4221, Folder 16)
  - Post Office, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 4221, Folder 17)
  - Post Office, 1969-1975 (Offsite-box 4222, Folder 1-9)
  - Postal Activities Booklets, 1976 (Offsite-box 4222, Folder 10-11)
  - Postal Calculation: Time Story, 1975 (Offsite-box 4222, Folder 12)
  - Postal Charts, 1975 (Offsite-box 4222, Folder 13)
  - Postal: Congress, 1975 (Offsite-box 4222, Folder 14)
  - Postal Classification, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 4222, Folder 15-19)
  - Postal Classification, 1976 (Offsite-box 4223, Folder 1-4)
  - Postal: Heiskell Leave-Behinds, 1975 (Offsite-box 4223, Folder 5)
  - Postal Legislation, 1974 (Offsite-box 4223, Folder 6-8)
  - Postal Procedures, 1975 (Offsite-box 4223, Folder 9)
  - Postal Rate Case, 1971-1975 (Offsite-box 4223, Folder 10-12)
  - Postal Rate Commission (PRC) Classification III, 1976 (Offsite-box 4223, Folder 13-15)
  - Postal Rate and Fee Changes, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 4223, Folder 16-22)
  - Postal Rate and Fee Changes, 1976 (Offsite-box 4224, Folder 1-2)
  - Postal Statistics, 1973 (Offsite-box 4224, Folder 3)
  - Postal Update, 1974 (Offsite-box 4224, Folder 4)
  - Postal: United States Postal Service (USPS), 1973-1975 (Offsite-box 4224, Folder 5-6)
  - Presentations (Postal Charts), 1975 (Offsite-box 4224, Folder 7)
  - R74-1: Brief on Exceptions, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 4224, Folder 8)
  - R74-1: Postal Rates and Fees, 1975 (Offsite-box 4224, Folder 9-10)
  - R76-1: Address Correction, undated (Offsite-box 4224, Folder 11-12)
  - R76-1: Fees for Special Services, 1976 (Offsite-box 4224, Folder 13)
  - R76-1: Initial Brief of Magazine Publishers Association (MPA), 1976 (Offsite-box 4224, Folder 14)
  - R76-1: Initial Brief of Time Incorporated, 1976 (Offsite-box 4224, Folder 15-16)
  - R76-1: Postal Rate Case Decision, 1976 (Offsite-box 4224, Folder 17)
  - R76-1: Postal Rates and Fees, 1976 (Offsite-box 4224, Folder 18-19)
  - R76-1: Postal Rates and Fees, 1976 (Offsite-box 4225, Folder 1-2)
  - R76-1: Reply Briefs, 1976 (Offsite-box 4225, Folder 3)
  - R76-1: Oral Argument, 1976 (Offsite-box 4225, Folder 4)
  - Rate Case III, 1975 (Offsite-box 4225, Folder 5)
  - Rate Hearing Transcripts, 1976 (Offsite-box 4225, Folder 6)
  - Reader's Digest, 1973 (Offsite-box 4225, Folder 7)
  - Revenue Sources, undated (Offsite-box 4225, Folder 8)
  - Richard J. Barber, 1974 (Offsite-box 4225, Folder 9)
  - Senate Bill S2844 (McGee Bill), 1976 (Offsite-box 4225, Folder 10-11)
  - Senate Hearings, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 4225, Folder 12-15)
  - Senate Reports, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 4225, Folder 16)
  - Senator Goldwater/Terry Emerson, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 4225, Folder 17)
  - Shoppers: Local, 1975 (Offsite-box 4225, Folder 18)
  - Sirica Ruling [Associated Third Class Mail Users (ATCMU)], 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 4225, Folder 19)
  - State's Interrogatories, 1975 (Offsite-box 4225, Folder 20)
  - Study: Criteria and Methodology for Designing Mail Classification Systems, 1974 (Offsite-box 4226, Folder 1)
  - Study: Red Tag vs. Non-Red Tag Mail, 1975 (Offsite-box 4226, Folder 2)
  - Testimony: First Rate Case, 1971-1975 (Offsite-box 4226, Folder 3-6)
  - Time Inc. Memos (Miscellaneous Postal Problems), 1975 (Offsite-box 4226, Folder 7)
  - Time Story and Essay, 1975 (Offsite-box 4226, Folder 8-13)
  - Time-Life Books Alternate Delivery, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 4226, Folder 14)
  - Total Market Coverage (Preprints), 1975 (Offsite-box 4226, Folder 15)
  - United States Postal Rate Commission, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 4226, Folder 16-17)
  - United States Postal Service, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 4226, Folder 18-21)
  - United States Postal Service, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 4227, Folder 1-6)
  - Washington Updates, 1975 (Offsite-box 4227, Folder 7)
- Series III. Cost Ascertainment Reports, 1949-1968; 1 Linear feet in 1 record carton
  Series III consists of cost ascertainment reports issued by the United States Post Office Department reporting the costs of delivering various classes and kind of mail and providing other services.
  Series III is arranged alphabetically.
  - Cost Ascertainment Reports, 1949-1968 (Offsite-box 4228, Folder 1-9)
- Series IV. Direct Mail Exhibits, 1969-1971; 0.8 Linear feet in 1 record carton
  Series IV consists of examples of direct mailings sent by Time Inc. to market its magazines. The examples are marked "defendant's exhibit", but no further information about their use is present.
  Series IV is arranged alphabetically.
  - Direct Mail Exhibits, 1969-1971 (Offsite-box 4227, Folder 8-14)
- Series V. Raymond J. Mitchell Files, 1976-1978; 1.5 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
  Series V consists of Raymond J. "Ray" Mitchell's files on changes in postal rates and laws. During this time Mitchell was Director of Time Inc.'s Alternative Distribution program which studied ways of delivering Time Inc's magazines through non-postal methods such as newspaper carrier and private delivery companies and so the changing costs of postal delivery for Time Inc. was of direct professional interest to him; he also had responsibility for Time Inc.'s activities with the Postal Rate Commission. The contents are similar to Series II, being reports from congressional proceedings on changes in postal rates and law. This includes witness testimony, questions given and answered to and by various parties, and proposed legislation.
  Source: Time Inc. Bio Files, MS 3009-RG 2, New-York Historical Society.
  Series V is arranged alphabetically.
  - Briefs of the Officer of the Commission, undated (Offsite-box 4229, Folder 1-2)
  - Interrogatories, 1976 (Offsite-box 4229, Folder 3-12)
    American Business Press
    Dow Jones
    Magazines Publishers Association (MPA)
    Meredith Corporation
    Miscellaneous
    Reader's Digest
    Time, Inc.
    United States Postal Service (USPS)
  - Mail Classification Schedule Proceedings, 1976-1978 (Offsite-box 4229, Folder 13-17)
  - Opinions and Recommended Decisions, 1977 (Offsite-box 4229, Folder 18-20)
  - Proposed Changes, 1977 (Offsite-box 4230, Folder 1)
  - Stipulation and Agreement, 1978 (Offsite-box 4230, Folder 2)
  - Witnesses, 1976-1978 (Offsite-box 4230, Folder 3-11)
    Arthur Eden
    Benjamin J. Bailer
    Chapin Carpenter
    Charles S. Mill
    Charles W. King
    Evan S. Ingels
    Magazine Publishers Association
    Paul D. Kagan
    Paul E. Postelnek
  - Working Papers, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 4230, Folder 12)
- Series VI. Winston H. Cox Files, 1974-1977; 1.5 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
  Winston H. "Tony" Cox was Assistant to the Group Vice-President for Magazines during the time period represented in these files, giving him a professional interest in the cost of postal delivery for Time Inc.'s magazines and potential changes due to new legislation. His files included postal-related bills put before Congress, articles written by Senator Barry Goldwater and Andrews Heiskell, Chairman of Time Inc., on the topic of changes to postal rates, information on Time Inc. postal expenses, and information and correspondence on specific subjects related to postal delivery such as if news periodicals should be considered a public service, the possibility of phasing increases in postal rates over time, and privately-owned alternatives to the United States Postal Service for mail delivery.
  Series VI is arranged alphabetically.
  - 3/22 Meeting, 1974 (Offsite-box 4230, Folder 13)
  - 30-Day Rule, 1975 (Offsite-box 4230, Folder 14)
  - Bills, 1975-1977 (Offsite-box 4230, Folder 15-21)
    Buckley Bill
    H.R. 10109
    Hanley Bill
    McGee Compromise Bill
    McGovern Bill
    Miscellaneous Bills
  - Classification: Phase III, 1976 (Offsite-box 4231, Folder 1)
  - Contact with Congressmen, 1974-1976 (Offsite-box 4231, Folder 2)
  - Electronic Funds Transfer, 1975 (Offsite-box 4231, Folder 3)
  - Goldwater Article, 1976 (Offsite-box 4231, Folder 4)
  - Goldwater/Koch, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 4231, Folder 5)
  - Heiskell Open Letters, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 4231, Folder 6-7)
  - Legal Expenses, 1973-1976 (Offsite-box 4231, Folder 8)
  - Mailers' Technical Advisory Committee (MTAC), 1976 (Offsite-box 4231, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 4231, Folder 10)
  - National Association of Letter Carriers, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 4231, Folder 11)
  - Phasing, 1974-1976 (Offsite-box 4231, Folder 12)
  - Private Express, 1976 (Offsite-box 4231, Folder 13)
  - Proposed Amendments to 39 USC 3622(b), 1977 (Offsite-box 4231, Folder 14)
  - Protest Over Rate Increases, 1976 (Offsite-box 4231, Folder 15)
  - Public Service Appropriations, 1976 (Offsite-box 4231, Folder 16)
  - Testimony to Committees, 1976 (Offsite-box 4231, Folder 17)
  - Time Inc. Postal Budget, 1975 (Offsite-box 4231, Folder 18)
  - Tony Cox Correspondence, 1976 (Offsite-box 4231, Folder 19)